<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</origin><pubdate>20170531</pubdate><title>Hydrologic Unit Code 8 Watersheds of Alberta</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><onlink>https://maps.alberta.ca/genesis/rest/services/Hydrologic_Unit_Code_Watersheds_of_Alberta</onlink><onlink>https://maps.alberta.ca/genesis/services/Hydrologic_Unit_Code_Watersheds_of_Alberta/Latest/MapServer/WMSServer </onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>This dataset is produced for the Government of Alberta and is available to the general public.  Please consult the Distribution Information of this metadata for the appropriate contact to acquire this dataset.  

The Hydrologic Unit Code (HUC) Watersheds of Alberta represents a collection of four nested hierarchically structured drainage basin feature classes that have been created using the Hydrologic Unit Code system of classification developed by the United States Geological Survey (USGS) with accommodation to reflect the pre-existing Canadian classification system.  The pour points associated with the delineation of these watersheds have also been included as a point feature class.  The HUC Watersheds of Alberta consist of successively smaller hydrologic units that nest within larger hydrologic units, resulting in a hierarchal grouping of alphanumerically-coded watersheds feature classes.  These nesting watersheds feature classes were created using ArcHydro Tools v.2 (Alberta Environment and Parks) and are subject to periodic review and update. There are currently individual feature classes for HUC 2 (coarsest level), HUC 4, HUC 6, HUC 8 and HUC 10 (finest level).  These are all contained within a single feature dataset.  The HUC Watersheds of Alberta co-exists with the Watersheds of Alberta (GOA) as well as a number of other non-GOA watersheds datasets such as the Prairie Farm Rehabilitation Administration watersheds data published by Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada.  The alphanumeric watershed coding follows the USGS system and also has a direct link to the Environment Canada Water Survey of Canada coding (as outlined by departmental Water Policy and Operations staff).  Where possible, Water Survey of Canada regions (00XX level) were approximated by the HUC 6 level of delineation but some exceptions will be noted.  Further delineation past the HUC 10 level may be required where smaller, more refined watershed units are needed. More information on the USGS hydrologic units can be found at http://water.usgs.gov/GIS/huc.html.  It should be noted that the HUC Watersheds of Alberta feature class polygons may be represented as multipart polygons (i.e. there may be only one record in the database associated with more than one polygon). Multipart polygons are typically located in the same watershed or basin where by two (or more) polygons flow into another province or territory. Multipart polygons may be exploded into single part polygons if required.

The Hydrologic Unit Code 8 Watersheds of Alberta is a feature class within the Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta feature dataset that represents a seamless basin-wide coverage that falls completely within the Hydrologic Unit Code 6 Watersheds of Alberta.  The coding is an eight-digit numeric code with the last two digits representing the unique identifier for the HUC 8 watershed.  The first six digits represent the enclosing HUC 6 watershed.  There are 422 polygons within this feature class ranging from five to 5 593 square kilometres in area with a mean area of 1 570 square kilometres.  Most of the HUC 8 watersheds are larger than 100 square kilometres and are typically more than 500 square kilometres in area.  There are four watersheds that are co-incident with the HUC 2 watersheds, five watersheds that are co-incident with the HUC 4 watersheds and 27 watersheds that are co-incident with the HUC 6 watersheds where the enclosing watersheds have not been subdivided.  There are generally one to 45 subdivisions of the HUC 2 watersheds, one to 18 subdivisions of the HUC 4 watersheds and one to five subdivisions of the HUC 6 watersheds present.  The HUC 8 watersheds have been attributed with the Water Survey Canada region code and a basin name.  The basin names follow the names associated with the HUC 2 watersheds but not the names associated with the Watersheds of Alberta 2011.  The HUC 8 watersheds have not yet been further subdivided.

Note that this dataset replaces the Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta released on October 16, 2015.  An area of approximately 3 381 hectares was deleted from HUC 11010404 (ELK RIVER) and appended to HUC 11010401 (BRAZEAU RIVER). The area amended is deemed to be part of the Brazeau Reservoir as opposed to the Elk River.

Update March 09, 2017 – The section of the Red Deer River immediately downstream of the Gleniffer Lake Dam was appended to HUC 08010301 (RED DEER RIVER AND SYLVAN LAKE). The area was removed from HUC 08010201 (RED DEER RIVER AND GLENIFFER LAKE) and was approximately 2700 hectares in size.

Update May 07, 2021 - Portions of the Belly (04010302) and Waterton (04010301) River watersheds were modified. Original delineations had the Lower Belly River as part of the Waterton River. This portion of the Belly River has been added to the Belly River Watershed HUC8, and was approximately 60,720 hectares in size</abstract><purpose>The Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta collection of feature classes is intended to define hydrologic units that form a standardized baseline which covers the province of Alberta. Successively smaller hydrologic units are nested within larger hydrologic units to create hierarchal watershed boundaries. These standard units are based on sound hydrologic principles (flow direction) and have been reconciled between and within the feature classes that form the dataset. Existing high resolution watersheds or catchment polygons have been collated into larger watershed units to achieve the hierarchical, nested polygon dataset structure.</purpose><supplinf>Watershed boundaries will vary between existing watershed/basin GIS layers available from the Government of Alberta and the Government of Canada. The user takes full responsibility understanding the spatial and temporal limitations of the HUC Watersheds of Alberta. More information concerning data sources used can be found within the department using the keywords listed below. Updates to this dataset will not necessarily be performed upon further review of existing watershed units. All rights reserved. HUC Watersheds of Alberta data is subject to change without notice. The Government of Alberta assumes no responsibility for discrepancies at time of use. Watershed unit delineation follows ArcHydro Tools v2 process, as outlined by the ArcHydro Tools Community of Practice (COP). Scale and accuracy of the HUC Watersheds of Alberta mimic the scale and accuracy of data contained in ArcHydro Tools geodatabase. Metadata is available for those datasets.</supplinf></descript><spdom><bounding><westbc>-120.902231</westbc><eastbc>-108.457295</eastbc><northbc>60.095171</northbc><southbc>48.894798</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>None</themekt><themekey>drainage area</themekey><themekey>watershed</themekey><themekey>catchment</themekey><themekey>HUC</themekey><themekey>hydrologic</themekey><themekey>basin</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt><themekey>inlandWaters</themekey><themekey>geoscientificInformation</themekey></theme><place><placekt>Alberta Geographic Names (GNS)</placekt><placekey>Alberta</placekey></place><place><placekt>None</placekt><placekey>North America</placekey><placekey>Mid-latitude</placekey><placekey>Northern Hemisphere</placekey><placekey>Canada</placekey><placekey>Alberta</placekey><placekey>Western Hemisphere</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>General Public: For conditional general public use. User must accept terms and conditions in a product license agreement before obtaining data. Government of Alberta Ministries: Conditional access to this data for internal business purposes is available to Government of Alberta Ministries and authorized agencies through Informatics Branch of Alberta Environment and Parks.</accconst><useconst>General Public: This digital data is protected under copyright to the Government of Alberta with all rights reserved and is subject to the conditions outlined in the Informatics Branch License Agreement for Digital Data. Government of Alberta Ministries: Government of Alberta Ministries and authorized agencies may conditionally use this data for internal business purposes which includes conditional sharing of the data with other third parties (i.e. contractors, stakeholders) if necessary for reasonable use of the data relating to the provision of services to the Crown as represented by each Ministry.</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</cntorg><cntper>Chad Sherburne</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Provincial Programs Delivery Branch, Operations Division</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>9920 - 108 Street</address><address>2nd Floor, Great West Life Building</address><city>Edmonton</city><state>Alberta</state><postal>T5K 2M4</postal><country>CA</country></cntaddr><cntemail>Chad.Sherburne@gov.ab.ca</cntemail><hours>08:15 to 16:30, Monday to Friday</hours><cntinst>This is the point of contact regarding the creation of, and characteristics of the data set. Queries about the creation of the dataset submitted through facsimile or electronic mail must include the salutation "Attention: Chad Sherburne, Provincial Programs Delivery Branch, Operations Division; Dataset: "Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta". For Distribution Information contact instructions, refer to the Distribution Information section of this metadata record. For Metadata Information contact instructions, refer to the Metadata Reference Information section of this metadata record.</cntinst></cntinfo></ptcontac><datacred>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</datacred><secinfo><secsys>GOA Data and Information Security Classification</secsys><secclass>Unclassified</secclass><sechandl>https://imtpolicy.sp.alberta.ca/standards/pdf/Data-and-Information-Security-Classification-Standard.pdf</sechandl></secinfo><native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.1.1.3176</native><crossref><citeinfo><origin>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</origin><pubdate>20140815</pubdate><title>Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta</title><othercit>There are 6 feature classes within the Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta feature dataset: HUC 2, HUC 4, HUC 6, HUC 8 and HUC 10 (coarsest to finest) plus the Pour Points. </othercit></citeinfo></crossref><crossref><citeinfo><pubinfo><pubplace>Edmonton, Alberta</pubplace><publish>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</publish></pubinfo><origin>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</origin><pubdate>20141231</pubdate><title>Watersheds of Alberta (GOA)</title><geoform>vector digital data</geoform><othercit>Previous versions of this data set have been made available as "Watersheds of Alberta 2011", "Watersheds of Alberta", and "Drainage Basins of Alberta". All of these former data sets are no longer valid and have been superseded by Watersheds of Alberta (GOA).</othercit></citeinfo></crossref></idinfo><dataqual><logic>The underlying data used to create the HUC Watersheds of Alberta are associated with various degrees of accuracy. There may be inconsistency in the spatial accuracy as a result. All HUC Watersheds of Alberta feature classes within the HUC Watersheds of Alberta feature dataset have been topologically reconciled between and within the feature classes for boundary alignment and gaps. The geometry has been checked and repaired.</logic><complete>This dataset is complete for all feature classes for the province of Alberta. No delineation coarser than HUC level 2 or finer than HUC level 10 is publically available.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>The positional accuracy of the watershed boundaries will vary according to the accuracy of the source data.</horizpar></horizpa></posacc><lineage><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">W:\Working\20170324_HUCMetadata\HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta</srcused><procdate Sync="TRUE">20170419</procdate><proctime Sync="TRUE">12262300</proctime></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><esriterm Name="HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom code="4" Sync="TRUE"></efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">422</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.0001</absres><ordres>0.0001</ordres></coordrep><plandu>meter</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn><ellips>GRS 1980</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis><denflat>298.257222101</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed Name="HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta"><enttyp><enttypl>HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta</enttypl><enttypd>Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta level 8 delineation</enttypd><enttypds>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</enttypds><enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">422</enttypc></enttyp><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl><attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">OBJECTID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">10</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC_8</attrlabl><attrdef>The 8-digit Hydrologic Unit Code for level 8 watershed delineation.</attrdef><attrdefs>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</attrdefs><attalias Sync="TRUE">HUC_8</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">12</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC_6</attrlabl><attrdefs>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</attrdefs><attrdef>The 6-digit Hydrologic Unit Code for level 6 watershed delineation.</attrdef><attalias Sync="TRUE">HUC_6</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">12</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC_4</attrlabl><attrdefs>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</attrdefs><attrdef>The 4-digit Hydrologic Unit Code for level 4 watershed delineation.</attrdef><attalias Sync="TRUE">HUC_4</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">12</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC_2</attrlabl><attrdefs>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</attrdefs><attrdef>The 2-digit Hydrologic Unit Code for level 2 watershed delineation (coarsest level).</attrdef><attalias Sync="TRUE">HUC_2</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">12</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>WSC_CODE</attrlabl><attrdefs>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</attrdefs><attrdef>Water Survey of Canada region code</attrdef><attalias Sync="TRUE">WSC_CODE</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">18</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl><attrdefs>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</attrdefs><attrdef>The river or stream name attached to the Hydrologic Unit Code 8 watershed.  Note that upper, middle and lower designations may be applied where the river mainstem has been split</attrdef><attalias Sync="TRUE">NAME</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">36</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>BASIN</attrlabl><attrdefs>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</attrdefs><attrdef>Basin name, which closely follows the name associated with the HUC 2 watershed.</attrdef><attalias Sync="TRUE">BASIN</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">24</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl><attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom></attrdomv><attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl>GlobalID</attrlabl><attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs><attrdef>Global unique identifier</attrdef><attalias Sync="TRUE">GlobalID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">38</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Leng</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Leng</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr><attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Area</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">SHAPE_Area</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Double</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">19</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">Esri</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr></detailed></eainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</cntorg></cntorgp><cntpos>Data Distribution Unit, Information and Data Provisioning Services, Informatics Branch, Corporate Services Division</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>14th Floor Oxbridge Place</address><address>9820 - 106 Street NW</address><city>Edmonton</city><state>Alberta</state><postal>T5K2J6</postal><country>Canada</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>7804277374</cntvoice><cntfax>7804220712</cntfax><cntemail>AEP.Data@gov.ab.ca </cntemail><hours>08:15 to 16:30 Monday to Friday</hours><cntinst>This is the point of contact regarding distribution of the data set. Queries about distribution of the data set submitted through facsimile or electronic mail must include the salutation "Attention: Data Distribution Unit, Information and Data Provisioning Services, Informatics Branch, Corporate Services Division; Dataset: Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta". For Metadata Information contact instructions, refer to the Metadata Reference Information section of this metadata record.</cntinst></cntinfo></distrib><resdesc>Offline data</resdesc><distliab>The user agrees that the information and each part thereof, any formatting or presentation thereof, any storage media on which it is provided, and any communication of any kind, incidental or in relation thereto, is provided to the user by the Minister and the Crown without warranty or representation as to any matter including but not limited to whether the information and storage media is correct, accurate or free from error, defect, danger, or hazard, and whether it is otherwise useful or suitable for any use the user may make of it. The Crown in right of Alberta, the Minister and her employees and agents, shall not be liable for any claims, costs, losses, or damages, including any special, indirect, incidental or consequential loss or damage, which the user may incur or experience as a result of the use or possession of the information or associated storage media.</distliab><stdorder><digform><digtinfo><formname>ESRI File Geodatabase</formname><formspec>ESRI File Geodatabase</formspec><filedec>File compression technology shall be utilized when required.</filedec></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><accinstr>FTP (File Transfer Protocol) is available, with the exception of data exceeding reasonable size limits or when corporate restrictions have been implemented in which the data will be delivered using alternative methods. Instructions on how to download data placed on our FTP site will be communicated when the data is ready for delivery.</accinstr></onlinopt></digtopt></digform><fees>Fee Free</fees><ordering>All requests for data / information are accepted via email, FAX, or Canada Post. All requests must include: Government of Alberta Ministry Name / Business Area Name, Physical Address, Contact Person Name(s), Phone and FAX Numbers, email Address, list of products requested, the geographic extent of the request (where product options are available - expressed by NTS block(s), township(s), etc), the delivery option required ( on-line / offline ), the data format when multiple formats are offered, and the intended use of the data.</ordering><turnarnd>Requests for information are processed and completed in order of receipt with the exception of Alberta Environment and Parks requests that are authorized as priority status. All requests for information are completed with five (5) working days of receiving the request wherever possible.</turnarnd><digform><digtinfo><formname>ESRI Shapefile</formname><formspec>ESRI Shapefile</formspec><filedec>File compression technology shall be utilized when required.</filedec></digtinfo><digtopt><onlinopt><accinstr>FTP (File Transfer Protocol) is available, with the exception of data exceeding reasonable size limits or when corporate restrictions have been implemented in which the data will be delivered using alternative methods. Instructions on how to download data placed on our FTP site will be communicated when the data is ready for delivery.</accinstr></onlinopt></digtopt></digform></stdorder><techpreq>To utilize digital information, specialized graphics or GIS software (i.e. ArcInfo, ArcView, ArcGIS, or MicroStation) may be required.</techpreq><custom>Limited custom order processing of Informatics Branch information may be available to Alberta Environment and Parks personnel and contractors working on behalf of the Ministry.</custom><availabl><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>Monday to Friday</caldate><time>08:15 to 16:30</time></sngdate></timeinfo></availabl></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20170531</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntorgp><cntorg>Alberta Environment and Parks, Government of Alberta</cntorg><cntper>Chad Sherburne</cntper></cntorgp><cntpos>Provincial Programs Delivery Branch, Operations Division</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype><address>9920 - 108 Street</address><address>2nd Floor, Great West Life Building</address><city>Edmonton</city><state>Alberta</state><postal>T5K 2M4</postal><country>CA</country></cntaddr><cntemail>Chad.Sherburne@gov.ab.ca</cntemail><hours>08:15 to 16:30, Monday to Friday</hours><cntinst>This is the point of contact regarding the creation of, and characteristics of, metadata for the data set. Queries about the creation and/or characteristics of the metadata submitted through facsimile or electronic mail must include the salutation "Attention: Chad Sherburne, Provincial Programs Delivery Branch, Operations Division; Dataset: "Hydrologic Unit Code Watersheds of Alberta". For Distribution Information contact instructions, refer to the Distribution Information section of this metadata record.</cntinst></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv><mettc>local time</mettc></metainfo><Esri><ModDate>20210615</ModDate><ModTime>10523000</ModTime><CreaDate>20210615</CreaDate><CreaTime>09081600</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><ArcGISstyle>FGDC CSDGM Metadata</ArcGISstyle><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\goa\appsdata\GIS_AEP\PGC\ELC\Watershed\Alberta_Gov\HUC_Watersheds\2_released\HydrologicUnitCodeWatershedsOfAlberta\HydrologicUnitCodeWatershedsOfAlberta\Data\Shapefile\10TM_Offset\HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation><itemName Sync="TRUE">HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">002</imsContentType><nativeExtBox><westBL Sync="TRUE">170844.329600</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">865133.515000</eastBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">5425575.486700</southBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">6659344.340000</northBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></nativeExtBox><itemSize Sync="TRUE">43.718</itemSize></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="W:\HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta" dest="\\cns1\elc\Watershed\Alberta_Gov\HUC_Watersheds\3_updated\HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta" date="20160401" time="07361000"/></copyHistory><coordRef><type Sync="TRUE">Projected</type><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn><csUnits Sync="TRUE">Linear Unit: Meter (1.000000)</csUnits><projcsn Sync="TRUE">NAD_1983_10TM_AEP_Forest</projcsn><peXml Sync="TRUE">&lt;ProjectedCoordinateSystem xsi:type='typens:ProjectedCoordinateSystem' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns:xs='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema' xmlns:typens='http://www.esri.com/schemas/ArcGIS/10.7'&gt;&lt;WKT&gt;PROJCS[&amp;quot;NAD_1983_10TM_AEP_Forest&amp;quot;,GEOGCS[&amp;quot;GCS_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,DATUM[&amp;quot;D_North_American_1983&amp;quot;,SPHEROID[&amp;quot;GRS_1980&amp;quot;,6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM[&amp;quot;Greenwich&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Degree&amp;quot;,0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION[&amp;quot;Transverse_Mercator&amp;quot;],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Easting&amp;quot;,500000.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;False_Northing&amp;quot;,0.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Central_Meridian&amp;quot;,-115.0],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Scale_Factor&amp;quot;,0.9992],PARAMETER[&amp;quot;Latitude_Of_Origin&amp;quot;,0.0],UNIT[&amp;quot;Meter&amp;quot;,1.0],AUTHORITY[&amp;quot;EPSG&amp;quot;,3400]]&lt;/WKT&gt;&lt;XOrigin&gt;-5118700&lt;/XOrigin&gt;&lt;YOrigin&gt;-9994100&lt;/YOrigin&gt;&lt;XYScale&gt;450625831.97791648&lt;/XYScale&gt;&lt;ZOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/ZOrigin&gt;&lt;ZScale&gt;10000&lt;/ZScale&gt;&lt;MOrigin&gt;-100000&lt;/MOrigin&gt;&lt;MScale&gt;10000&lt;/MScale&gt;&lt;XYTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/XYTolerance&gt;&lt;ZTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/ZTolerance&gt;&lt;MTolerance&gt;0.001&lt;/MTolerance&gt;&lt;HighPrecision&gt;true&lt;/HighPrecision&gt;&lt;WKID&gt;102184&lt;/WKID&gt;&lt;LatestWKID&gt;3400&lt;/LatestWKID&gt;&lt;/ProjectedCoordinateSystem&gt;</peXml></coordRef><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files\arcgis\pro\Resources\ArcToolbox\toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\CalculateField" Date="20230104" Time="142316">CalculateField HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta HUC_8 "AB-"+!HUC_8! "Python 3" # Text</Process></lineage><LayerFile>{"type":"CIMLayerDocument","version":"2.7.0","build":26828,"layers":["CIMPATH=map/hydrologicunitcode8watershedsofalberta.xml"],"layerDefinitions":[{"type":"CIMFeatureLayer","name":"HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta","uRI":"CIMPATH=map/hydrologicunitcode8watershedsofalberta.xml","sourceModifiedTime":{"type":"TimeInstant"},"useSourceMetadata":true,"description":"HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta","layerElevation":{"type":"CIMLayerElevationSurface","mapElevationID":"{954C4D2A-8C62-486D-934D-17173AE960F2}"},"expanded":true,"layerType":"Operational","showLegends":true,"visibility":true,"displayCacheType":"Permanent","maxDisplayCacheAge":5,"showPopups":true,"serviceLayerID":-1,"refreshRate":-1,"refreshRateUnit":"esriTimeUnitsSeconds","blendingMode":"Alpha","autoGenerateFeatureTemplates":true,"featureElevationExpression":"0","featureTable":{"type":"CIMFeatureTable","displayField":"NAME","editable":true,"dataConnection":{"type":"CIMStandardDataConnection","workspaceConnectionString":"DATABASE=E:\\CE_Watersheds\\HydrologicUnitCodeWatershedsOfAlberta\\Data\\Shapefile\\10TM_Offset","workspaceFactory":"Shapefile","dataset":"HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta","datasetType":"esriDTFeatureClass"},"studyAreaSpatialRel":"esriSpatialRelUndefined","searchOrder":"esriSearchOrderSpatial"},"htmlPopupEnabled":true,"selectable":true,"featureCacheType":"Session","displayFiltersType":"ByScale","featureBlendingMode":"Alpha","labelClasses":[{"type":"CIMLabelClass","expressionTitle":"Custom","expression":"$feature.NAME","expressionEngine":"Arcade","featuresToLabel":"AllVisibleFeatures","maplexLabelPlacementProperties":{"type":"CIMMaplexLabelPlacementProperties","featureType":"Polygon","avoidPolygonHoles":true,"canOverrunFeature":true,"canPlaceLabelOutsidePolygon":true,"canRemoveOverlappingLabel":true,"canStackLabel":true,"connectionType":"Unambiguous","constrainOffset":"NoConstraint","contourAlignmentType":"Page","contourLadderType":"Straight","contourMaximumAngle":90,"enableConnection":true,"featureWeight":0,"fontHeightReductionLimit":4,"fontHeightReductionStep":0.5,"fontWidthReductionLimit":90,"fontWidthReductionStep":5,"graticuleAlignmentType":"Straight","keyNumberGroupName":"Default","labelBuffer":15,"labelLargestPolygon":true,"labelPriority":-1,"labelStackingProperties":{"type":"CIMMaplexLabelStackingProperties","stackAlignment":"ChooseBest","maximumNumberOfLines":3,"minimumNumberOfCharsPerLine":3,"maximumNumberOfCharsPerLine":24,"separators":[{"type":"CIMMaplexStackingSeparator","separator":" ","splitAfter":true},{"type":"CIMMaplexStackingSeparator","separator":",","visible":true,"splitAfter":true}]},"lineFeatureType":"General","linePlacementMethod":"OffsetCurvedFromLine","maximumLabelOverrun":80,"maximumLabelOverrunUnit":"Point","minimumFeatureSizeUnit":"Map","multiPartOption":"OneLabelPerPart","offsetAlongLineProperties":{"type":"CIMMaplexOffsetAlongLineProperties","placementMethod":"BestPositionAlongLine","labelAnchorPoint":"CenterOfLabel","distanceUnit":"Percentage","useLineDirection":true},"pointExternalZonePriorities":{"type":"CIMMaplexExternalZonePriorities","aboveLeft":4,"aboveCenter":2,"aboveRight":1,"centerRight":3,"belowRight":5,"belowCenter":7,"belowLeft":8,"centerLeft":6},"pointPlacementMethod":"AroundPoint","polygonAnchorPointType":"GeometricCenter","polygonBoundaryWeight":0,"polygonExternalZones":{"type":"CIMMaplexExternalZonePriorities","aboveLeft":4,"aboveCenter":2,"aboveRight":1,"centerRight":3,"belowRight":5,"belowCenter":7,"belowLeft":8,"centerLeft":6},"polygonFeatureType":"General","polygonInternalZones":{"type":"CIMMaplexInternalZonePriorities","center":1},"polygonPlacementMethod":"HorizontalInPolygon","primaryOffset":1,"primaryOffsetUnit":"Point","removeExtraWhiteSpace":true,"repetitionIntervalUnit":"Point","rotationProperties":{"type":"CIMMaplexRotationProperties","rotationType":"Arithmetic","alignmentType":"Straight"},"secondaryOffset":100,"strategyPriorities":{"type":"CIMMaplexStrategyPriorities","stacking":1,"overrun":2,"fontCompression":3,"fontReduction":4,"abbreviation":5},"thinningDistanceUnit":"Point","truncationMarkerCharacter":".","truncationMinimumLength":1,"truncationPreferredCharacters":"aeiou","truncationExcludedCharacters":"0123456789","polygonAnchorPointPerimeterInsetUnit":"Point"},"name":"Class 1","priority":-1,"standardLabelPlacementProperties":{"type":"CIMStandardLabelPlacementProperties","featureType":"Line","featureWeight":"None","labelWeight":"High","numLabelsOption":"OneLabelPerName","lineLabelPosition":{"type":"CIMStandardLineLabelPosition","above":true,"inLine":true,"parallel":true},"lineLabelPriorities":{"type":"CIMStandardLineLabelPriorities","aboveStart":3,"aboveAlong":3,"aboveEnd":3,"centerStart":3,"centerAlong":3,"centerEnd":3,"belowStart":3,"belowAlong":3,"belowEnd":3},"pointPlacementMethod":"AroundPoint","pointPlacementPriorities":{"type":"CIMStandardPointPlacementPriorities","aboveLeft":2,"aboveCenter":2,"aboveRight":1,"centerLeft":3,"centerRight":2,"belowLeft":3,"belowCenter":3,"belowRight":2},"rotationType":"Arithmetic","polygonPlacementMethod":"AlwaysHorizontal"},"textSymbol":{"type":"CIMSymbolReference","symbol":{"type":"CIMTextSymbol","blockProgression":"TTB","depth3D":1,"extrapolateBaselines":true,"fontEffects":"Normal","fontEncoding":"Unicode","fontFamilyName":"Tahoma","fontStyleName":"Regular","fontType":"Unspecified","haloSize":1,"height":10,"hinting":"Default","horizontalAlignment":"Left","kerning":true,"letterWidth":100,"ligatures":true,"lineGapType":"ExtraLeading","symbol":{"type":"CIMPolygonSymbol","symbolLayers":[{"type":"CIMSolidFill","enable":true,"color":{"type":"CIMRGBColor","values":[0,0,0,100]}}]},"textCase":"Normal","textDirection":"LTR","verticalAlignment":"Bottom","verticalGlyphOrientation":"Right","wordSpacing":100,"billboardMode3D":"FaceNearPlane"}},"useCodedValue":true,"visibility":true,"iD":-1}],"renderer":{"type":"CIMSimpleRenderer","patch":"Default","symbol":{"type":"CIMSymbolReference","symbol":{"type":"CIMPolygonSymbol","symbolLayers":[{"type":"CIMSolidStroke","enable":true,"capStyle":"Round","joinStyle":"Round","lineStyle3D":"Strip","miterLimit":10,"width":0.69999999999999996,"color":{"type":"CIMRGBColor","values":[110,110,110,100]}},{"type":"CIMSolidFill","enable":true,"color":{"type":"CIMRGBColor","values":[252.449999999999989,228.97,207.009999999999991,100]}}]}}},"scaleSymbols":true,"snappable":true}]}</LayerFile></DataProperties><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncDate>20210615</SyncDate><SyncTime>10523000</SyncTime></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE"> Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.7.1.11595</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="search"><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode><westBL Sync="TRUE">-120.902231</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-108.457295</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">60.095171</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">48.894798</southBL></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode value="eng" Sync="TRUE"></languageCode><countryCode value="USA" Sync="TRUE"></countryCode></mdLang><mdChar><CharSetCd value="004" Sync="TRUE"></CharSetCd></mdChar><distInfo><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distFormat><distTranOps><transSize Sync="TRUE">43.718</transSize></distTranOps></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005" Sync="TRUE"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode code="3400" Sync="TRUE"></identCode><idCodeSpace Sync="TRUE">EPSG</idCodeSpace><idVersion Sync="TRUE">6.11(9.3.0.0)</idVersion></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><geometObjs Name="HydrologicUnitCode8WatershedsOfAlberta"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd value="002" Sync="TRUE"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">422</geoObjCnt></geometObjs><topLvl><TopoLevCd value="001" Sync="TRUE"></TopoLevCd></topLvl></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20210615</mdDateSt></metadata>
